

KJARTAN FRANKLÍN MAGNÚS

Address: Krusågade 16, København

Phone: +45 53807059

Email: kjartanfranklin@gmail.com

PROFILE

I hold an M.Sc. in Industrial Engineering and Management from the Technical University of Denmark and am currently part of the Graduate Program at Nexi Group. My background combines analytical experience from roles in finance and tech, including strategic analysis to support top management decision-making. I also have a strong personal interest in sports and music. Take a look at my website: www.kjartanfranklin.com for more.

KEY SKILLS

Industrial Engineering

Optimization

Business Development

Analysis & Decision Support

Excel, Python, SQL, Power BI

Good Presentation Skills

WORK EXPERIENCE

Graduate Program - Nets, part of Nexi Group - Copenhagen

2024 - Current

- Developed business cases for strategic decision making for Tap to Pay on iPhone.
- Developed actionable Power BI insights for Tap to Pay on iPhone, enabling data driven decision making.
- Led AI implementation projects in Salesforce to streamline processes and enhance operational efficiency.
- Enhanced the sales proposition for the data product LAKA reporting, driving alignment with customer needs and market trends.

Business Development Analyst - Sýn hf. - Reykjavík

2022 - 2024

- Strategic analysis to support top management decision-making. Delivered presentations and reports to the board of directors.
- Led several analyses for process optimisation of Visir.is, the largest news-website in Iceland, achieving a 23% increase in yearly revenue.
- Led analysis for IoT product development for Vodafone Iceland.
- Led several company-, and project evaluations for potential ventures.

Service Management Specialist - Arion Bank - Reykjavík

2021

- Developed a chatbot using artificial intelligence software for Arion Bank and Frjálsi pension fund.
- Responsible for inventory management of the banks' ATMs all across the country for a summer.
- Wrote numerous information pages accessible to the banks' service agents.

Service Agent - Arion Bank - Reykjavík

2019-2020

- Was consistently in the first to third place amongst service agents across the country, in metrics such as 'number
 of clients serviced' and 'products and services introduced to customers'.
- · Provided exceptional customer service to clients and helped educate customers on bank products and services.

EDUCATION

M.Sc. Industrial Engineering & Management

June 2024

Technical University of Denmark

• Thesis on investment decision making for alternative energy in the maritime sector. Grade: 10.

B.Sc. Industrial Engineering

June 2021

University of Iceland



KJARTAN FRANKLÍN MAGNÚS

Address: Krusågade 16, København

Phone: +45 53807059

Email: kjartanfranklin@gmail.com
Website: www.kjartanfranklin.com

LANGUAGES

• Icelandic: Native / Fluent

• English: Fluent

• Danish: Intermediate

ACTIVITIES & EXTRACURRICULARS

Facilitator - Technical University of Denmark

2023

• Facilitated a multidisciplinary team in an innovation project for Carlsberg. The team consisted of six engineering master students from various departments and backgrounds.

Fundraiser - University of Iceland

2021

 Raised financial support for the publication of the engineering student paper Vélarbrögð through various fundraising efforts.

President - Commercial College of Iceland

2017-2018

 President of the Student-Led Club NFVÍ Live. Organised and managed live broadcasts at various school events.

National Champion U21 - KR Reykjavik

2017

• National Champion of Iceland in the under 21's football league. Qualifying for the UEFA Youth League.